<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noël&#39;s Home on noelmrtn</title>
    <link>https://noelmrtn.fr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Noël&#39;s Home on noelmrtn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noelmrtn.fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Building a Magnetic Loop Antenna</title>
      <link>https://noelmrtn.fr/posts/loop_antenna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noelmrtn.fr/posts/loop_antenna/</guid>
      <description>Currently I am living within a parisian flat and I love doing HF&amp;hellip; So, I found in magloop antennas a good compromise in order to operate from the inside of my flat. I&amp;rsquo;ve looked for numerous antenna models, but for all of them the price is always high, at least 300€.
Antenna Design There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of designs available on the internet, the one I found the most interesting was made by OM0ET and him Ultralight MagLoop Antenna MC-20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://noelmrtn.fr/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noelmrtn.fr/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am Noël and I work as a Software Engineer (mostly a manager now) in Paris. My center of interests are: low and retro-technology (arduinos, minitel, esp32, &amp;hellip;), science (former physicist), and also amateur radio (F4JJD).
I began the college in Lyon, where I studied physics and chemistry. It&amp;rsquo;s how I discovered that the chemistry wasn&amp;rsquo;t made for me. So, I focused only on physics and especially on the theoretical side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amateur Radio Booklet</title>
      <link>https://noelmrtn.fr/hambooklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noelmrtn.fr/hambooklet/</guid>
      <description>The Amateur Radio Booklet consists in a summary of all the needed data when one operates. The booklet is global by design, thus one can find resources for all IARU regions.
Also, the booklet is fully open sourced! It is released under the CC BY-SA 4.0 license.
GitHub Repository Current PDF 2023 Edition, in preparation Current Work Final review of the content and chapter reorganization Release the 2023 Edition Preparing the first A5-printed copies Table of Contents Band Plans Digital Modes Morse Code International Beacon Project Radio Abbreviations Q Codes Classification of Emissions Radio Waves Electricity ITU Prefixes Units Mathematics ITU Regions ITU Alphabet </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
