<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noël&#39;s Home on noelmrtn</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Noël&#39;s Home on noelmrtn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Construction d&#39;une antenne long-fil EFHW multibande</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/efhw_antenna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/efhw_antenna/</guid>
      <description>Habitant en ville, il n&amp;rsquo;est pas simple de faire de la HF. Alors la majeure partie du temps j&amp;rsquo;opère en HF en portable avec mon Yaesu FT-817 et un mat SOTA beams de 7m. Quant à l&amp;rsquo;antenne, j&amp;rsquo;utilise une long fil de 10 mètres accordée sur la bande des 20 mètres. Plus précisément, c&amp;rsquo;est une antenne End-Fed Half-Wave (EFHW), que l&amp;rsquo;on traduirait probablement comme : antenne demie-onde alimentée par terminaison.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zig Threading Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zig_threading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zig_threading/</guid>
      <description>Prequel With the release of Zig 0.11.0, the language introduced channels like in Go. However, in the same release, they announced that the support of async functions is postponed (related Github issue); they expect their support for the release 0.13.0.&#xA;Initially, I wanted to test channels, but:&#xA;0.11.0 gets Channel, but unusable because it requires await functions 0.10.0 gets async/await support with the option -fstage1, but the Channel is not part of the language Finally, I switched to the solution of thread pools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prime Numbers Algorithm, in Zig and C</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zig_and_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zig_and_c/</guid>
      <description>A colleague of mine told me to try a new programming language named Zig. It is designed closely to C/C++ and is also inspired by Rust. I tried to learn Rust those last years as a replacement for C++. However, the syntax is too complex for me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled too much with the compiler&amp;hellip;&#xA;I tried Zig a few days ago with Zig Learn, which is a detailed tutorial to understand the basics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Building a Magnetic Loop Antenna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/loop_antenna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/loop_antenna/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I am living in a Parisian flat, and I love doing HF. But you probably know that the antenna length is proportional to wavelength, and dozens of meters cannot be found in a Parisian flat, believe me. So, I found mag-loop antennas a good compromise to operate from the inside of my flat. I&amp;rsquo;ve looked for numerous antenna models, but for all of them, the price is always high, at least 300€.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am Noël, a Software Engineer (mainly a manager now) in Paris. My centers of interest are low and retro-technology (Arduino, Minitel, esp32), science (former physicist), and amateur radio (F4JJD).&#xA;I began college in Lyon, where I studied physics and chemistry. Then, I focused only on fundamental physics, especially theoretical research. In 2013, I joined the CNRS (French Organization for Research) as a PhD student and pursued into the neutron-star physics field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amateur Radio Booklet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hambooklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hambooklet/</guid>
      <description>The Amateur Radio Booklet consists of a summary of all the needed data when one operates. The booklet is global by design. Thus, one can find resources for all IARU regions.&#xA;Also, the booklet is fully open-sourced under the CC BY-SA 4.0 license license.&#xA;GitHub 2024.1 Edition Table of Contents Band Plans Classification of Emissions Q Codes Morse Code Radio Abbreviations Digital Modes FT8, FT4 PSK, MFSK, Olivia RTTY WSPR Amateur Satellite ISS QO-100 International Beacon Project Beacon List Frequencies Radio Waves Propagation Solar Weather Antennas Standing Wave Ratio Electricity Kirchhoff&amp;rsquo;s Law Operation Amplifiers Filters &amp;amp; RLC ITU Prefixes Allocation ITU Regions ITU Alphabet QTH Locator Units International System Conversions Decibels Mathematics </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
